Guide to the Papers of Rev. Richards A. Zariņš, 1883-2008 M1938
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4. Speeches and writings
  - Sermons and related materials
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1973: August-October (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1973: November-December (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1974: January-March (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1974: April-June (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1974: June-July (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1974: July-October (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1974: October-December (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975: January-March (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975: April-June (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975: June-October (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975: October-November (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975: November-December (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1976: January-March (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1976: April-May (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1976: June-October (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1983: January-May (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1983: June-December (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1984: January-July (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1984: August-December (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1985: January-June (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1985: July-December (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1986: January-August (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1986: September-December (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1987: January- April (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1987: May-December (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1988: January-September (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1988: October-December (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1991: January-August (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1991: September-December (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1992: January-July (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1992: August-December (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1993: January- (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1994: January-May (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1994: June-December (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1995: January-April (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1995: May-December (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1999: January-May (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1999: June-December (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1949-1957 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1958-1967 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1968-1974 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1975-1979 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pasor's work journal, 1980-1986 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Christmas sermons and related materials. Pasor's work journal, 1987-1996 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Eulogies, ceremonial leaflets and related materials: Latvian Memorial Park in the Catskills, 1975-1987 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Eulogies, ceremonial leaflets and related materials: Latvian Memorial Park in the Catskills, 1988-2001 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Radio presentations: sermons and religious talks
    - Christian radio: Bringing Christ to the Nations, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Voice of America. Latvian Unit, 1951-1953 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Voice of America. Latvian Unit, 1954-1956 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Voice of America. Latvian Unit, 1957-1963 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Voice of America. Latvian Unit, 1982, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts
    - Handwritten manuscripts and materials, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts: Newspaper "Laiks", 1955-1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Typescripts: Newspaper "Laiks", 1995-2000. Undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Typescripts: Journal "Ceļa Biedrs", 1963-1992 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Typescripts: Newsletter "Baznīcas Ziņas", 1992-1999. Undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Typescripts: Newspaper "Svētdienas Rīts", 1992, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Typescripts: Newspaper "Universitas", 1983, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Typescripts: Titles of publications and dates not specified (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Typescript and materials: Autobiography of Rev. Richards Zariņš, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts and materials on Latvian sailors, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Typescript on history of Latvian fleet: no title, no date (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Typescript on history of Latvian fleet: no title, no fate (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Typescript on history of Latvian fleet: no title, no date (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Typescript: "Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York" by a group of authors, including Rev. Richards Zariņš: Chapters, editing, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Typescript: "Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York" by a group of authors, including Rev. Richards Zariņš: Chapters, editing, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Typescript: "Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York" by a group of authors, including Rev. Richards Zariņš: comments, critique, correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Typescript: "Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York" by a group of authors, including Rev. Richards Zariņš: comments, critique, correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Typescript: "Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York" by a group of authors, including Rev. Richards Zariņš: materials (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts for Latvian Encyclopedia, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Typescripts: Materials for bibliography (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Various typescripts and handwritten manuscripts: speeches, 1960-1996 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Typescripts and handwritten manuscripts: selection of sermons by Rev. Richards Zariņš and others (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Published articles in newspapers and journals
    - "Baznīcas Ziņas", 1942-1981 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "Baznīcas Ziņas", 1981-1996 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Ceļa Biedrs", 1956-2000 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Laiks", 1955-1997 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Mājas Draugs", 1950-1955 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Universitas", 1956-1986 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Latvijas Ev.-Lut. Baznīcas Kalendārs" and other publications (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Series 5. Private diaries and journals of meetings
  - Daily desk diaries, 1949-1950 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1952-1953 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1954-1955 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1956-1957 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1961-1962 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1963-1964 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1969-1970 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1973-1974 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diary, 1977; Meeting diaries, 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diary and meeting diary, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Daily desk diaries, 1996-1997 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Daily desk diary, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Daily desk diary, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Daily desk diary, 1999-2000 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Daily desk diary, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 5)
- Series 6. The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York and congregation
  - Congregational documents
    - Constitution and by-laws for The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York. Related documentation, 1946-2000 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Lists of parishioners, 1936-1949 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Lists and addresses of parishioners, 1975-1994 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Lists and addresses of the oldest parishioners, 1954-1989 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Individual questionnaires for the register of parishioners (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Annual reports of the congregation, 1947-1958 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Annual reports of the congregation, 1959-1969 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Annual reports of the congregation, 1970-1979 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Annual reports of the congregation, 1980-1987 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - The decisions of general meetings and board meetings. Minutes of board meetings, 1947-1953 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Galupville parish, Schoharie county, New York state. Documents, 1946-1949 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Church of the Holy Trinity. Documents and correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Internal parish correspondence, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Internal parish correspondence, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Internal parish correspondence, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Survey of the parishioners-immigrants regarding their losses during the communist regime, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Survey of the parishioners-immigrants regarding their losses during the communist regime, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1957-1958 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church. Parish in Hempsteade, Nassau county, New York state, 1954-1957 etc (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1961-1962 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1964 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous documents and internal parish correspondence, 1969-1979 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1980-1985 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1986-1989 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1990-1995 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1996-1998 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1999-2001 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Jamaica district. Miscellaneous documents, 1953-1972 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Jamaica district. Miscellaneous documents, 1973-1990 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Long Island Property. Long Island (Salas) Church. Miscellaneous documents,1962-1999 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Northern district. Bronx. Yonkers Church. Miscellaneous documents,1951-1990 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - New Jersey district. Miscellaneous documents,1963-1997 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Religious ceremonies
    - Agenda (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Agenda. Sunday worship services. Leaflets, 1946-1950. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Hymn books (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Lithurgical music. Texts and comments (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Lithurgical music. Texts and comments (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Lithurgical music. Music sheets (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Sunday worship services. Sacristan's notes about services. Leaflets, 1951-1952. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Sunday worship services. Leaflets, 1953-1960 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Sunday worship services. Leaflets, 1961-1994 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Baptism. The order for the baptism, leaflets, certificates, 1949-1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Confirmation doctrine and lessons (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Confirmation doctrine and lessons (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Lists of confirmands and related materials (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Materials related to confirmation: correspondence, invitations etc., 1949-1964 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Confirmation service. Leaflets, 1951-1989 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - The marriage ceremonies. Service leaflets and invitations, 1953-1969 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - The marriage ceremonies. Service leaflets and invitations, 1970-1992 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - The funeral service. Leaflets and obituaries, 1963-1999 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Obituaries of parish members. Death certificates. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New York: a constituent of the United Lutheran Church in America (ULCA)
    - Constitution of ULCA and related documents (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Documents related to cooperation of ULCA (later ELCA) and Latvian Church, including conferences, 1947-1989 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Parochial reports to ULCA, 1947-1957 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Financial documents sent to the Board of American Missions. Congregational budget, 1948-1954 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - ULCA guides and informative materials: booklets and miscellaneous papers (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - National Lutheran Council. News Bureau. Press releases, 1952-1976 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Unity of Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Churches in America
    - Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church Board: committee sessions, minutes of meetings, correspondence, 1949-1954 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church Board: committee sessions, correspondence, clippings, 1955-1956 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - The Federation of Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Congregations in America (LELDAA): circulars, reports, correspondence, clippings, 1957-1963 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - The Federation of Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Congregations in America (LELDAA): circulars, minutes of meetings, correspondence, clippings, 1964-1967 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - The Federation of Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Congregations in America (LELDAA): circulars, minutes of meetings, correspondence, clippings, 1968-1974 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church in America (LELBA): circulars, minutes of meetings of Supreme Board, Synodal meetings, correspondence, clippings, 1975-1986 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church in America (LELBA): circulars, minutes of meetings of Supreme Board, Synodal meetings, correspondence, clippings, 1987-1992 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - The Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church in America (LELBA): circulars, reports, Synodal papers, correspondence, clippings, 1993-1999 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Monthly "Ceļa Biedrs" (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Cooperation with different branches of Lutheran Church and baptists
    - Estonian Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1947-1952 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Estonian Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1953-1970 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Lithuanian Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1947-1962 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Swedish Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1946-1962 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - German Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1953-1960 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Finish Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1953-1962 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Other branches of Lutheran Church: Norway, Poland, Hungary, 1948-1959 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - The First Latvian Baptist Church of New York, 1947-1992 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Congregation and relief work for displaced people (DP) after the World War II
    - Latvian Nationality Conference Committee. Project on Latvian immigration, 1947-1948 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Latvian displaced people in Germany: DP camps, activities of Lutheran Church, 1946-1956 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      The materials consist of reports, correspondence, clippings, displaced person questionaires
    - Lists of Latvian addresses in the United States: New York, Boston, Philadelphia, Chicago, Washington, 1943-1949 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Lists of Latvian addresses in the United States: materials for the lists, 1947-1948 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Lists of Latvian addresses in the United States: Latvian Lutheran Congregations, different organizations and related materials, 1948-1949 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Lists of Latvian displaced persons: arrived in New York, 1946-1949 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Lists of Latvian displaced persons: drafts: arrived in New York in 1949 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Lists of Latvian displaced persons: arrived in New York in 1950 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Latvian Relief, Inc.: reports, announcements, correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Latvian Relief, Inc.: reports, correspondence, announcements, 1949-1951 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Latvian Relief, Inc.: lists of persons, relatives and friends, sought by Latvian refugees in Europe, 1946-1949 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - American Relief for Latvia, 1940-1948 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Micellaneous correspondence regarding assurances for immigration, 1947-1952. Roberts Hiršs, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - National Lutheran Council. Resettlement Service: progress reports, statements, correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - National Lutheran Council. Resettlement Service: progress reports, statements, correspondence, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - National Lutheran Council. Resettlement Service: progress reports, statements, correspondence, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - National Lutheran Council. Resettlement Service: progress reports, statements, correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - National Lutheran Council. Tabulated qualifications of displaced professional persons, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Ship newspaper “Unsere Muir Reise” on the USNS “General C.H. Muir”, January 11, 1951-January 20, 1951 (Flat-box 89, Folder 3)
    - Welcome of immigrants in the port of New York. S.S."Marine Shark" passenger list, 1949 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Displaced persons resettlement forms, 1949-1956. Blank forms (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Displaced orphan children. Immigration and adoption, 1948-1949 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Displaced persons, interned in Ellis Island, 1949-1950 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Ellis Island. Baltic refugees from Sweden, 1947-1950 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - National Lutheran Council. Lutheran Refugee Service: instructions, correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - The immigration applications affirmed by the congregation, 1953-1955 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Immigration case of Gertrude Kasparsons, 1949-1954 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - National Lutheran Council. Lutheran Refugee Service: Dossiers, correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Relief packages to displaced persons in Germany. Care "Food -Crusade" Programm: delivery receits, 1955-1958 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Relief packages to displased persons in Germany. Care "Food -Crusade" Programm: delivery receits, 1957-1958 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Relief packages to displased persons in Germany. Care "Food -Crusade" Programm: delivery receits, 1957-1958. Miscellaneous documents. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - National Lutheran Church, Church World Service, Lutheran World Relief, etc. on relief work and DP resettlement: booklets, leaflets and related materials (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - News Bureau. National Lutheran Council relases, 1947-1948 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Lutheran World Action Bulletin, Lutheran Welfare and related periodicals, 1947-1954 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Ladies Aid Committee
    - Activities: progress reports, statements, plans, correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Activities: statements, lists of members, correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Activities: announcements, reports, correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Activities: announcements, statements, correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Activities: announcements, reports, lists of members, correspondence, 1966-1998 (Box 63, Folder 3)